Pierre Eugène du Simitière collection LCP.DuSimitiere
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series XI. Papers relating to New York Politics, 1768-1771; [396.F] (Box 9)
  - Newspaper clipping by "Americanus", 1770 May 7 (Box 9, Folder (III).106-110)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).111-118)
  - Newspaper clipping by "Ironicus", undated (Box 9, Folder (III).119)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 14 (Box 9, Folder (III).123-128)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 21 (Box 9, Folder (III).129-133)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 21 (Box 9, Folder (III).134-136)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 24 (Box 9, Folder (III).137-140)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 28 (Box 9, Folder (III).142)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).147)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May (Box 9, Folder (III).151-154)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 May 31 (Box 9, Folder (III).156-158)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 4 (Box 9, Folder (III).160-165)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 4 (Box 9, Folder (III).166)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 1 (Box 9, Folder (III).168-173)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).174-178)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 21 (Box 9, Folder (III).184-188)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 11 (Box 9, Folder (III).189-194)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 18 (Box 9, Folder (III).195-200)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 24 (Box 9, Folder (III).201-206)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 25 (Box 9, Folder (III).207-211)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 19 (Box 9, Folder (III).212-213)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).215-217)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 26 (Box 9, Folder (III).218-225)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 2 (Box 9, Folder (III).226-232)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 2-6 (Box 9, Folder (III).233-238)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 June 26-July 18 (Box 9, Folder (III).239-244)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 18-19 (Box 9, Folder (III).245-250)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).251-253)
  - Manuscript regarding non-importation, 1770 July 11 (Box 9, Folder (III).254)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 23 (Box 9, Folder (III).255-263)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 26 (Box 9, Folder (III).264-270)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 July 21 (Box 9, Folder (III).271-276)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 August 16 (Box 9, Folder (III).277-279)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 August 7 (Box 9, Folder (III).282-287)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 August 20 (Box 9, Folder (III).288-296)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 August 27-29 (Box 9, Folder (III).297-301)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 August 28 (Box 9, Folder (III).302-308)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).309-314.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 October 15 (Box 9, Folder (III).315-322.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 November (Box 9, Folder (III).323-329)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).330-337)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (III).338-345)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 December (Box 9, Folder (III).345.5-351.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1770 December 24 (Box 9, Folder (III).352-355)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 January (Box 9, Folder (IV).1-6)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 February (Box 9, Folder (IV).7-13)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 March (Box 9, Folder (IV).13.5-19)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 March (Box 9, Folder (IV).20-31)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 April (Box 9, Folder (IV).31.5-38)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).40-45)
  - Newspaper clipping and notes, 1770 May and undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).46-52)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).53-55)
  - Letter sent to John Reade, Gabriel H. Ludlow and Uriah Hendricks, merchants, 1770 May 10 (Box 9, Folder (IV).57)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 July 11 (Box 9, Folder (IV).58-59)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).60)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).61)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).62-63)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 July (Box 9, Folder (IV).64-68)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 August (Box 9, Folder (IV).69-74)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).74.5-83)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).83.5-87)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).88)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 October (Box 9, Folder (IV).89-93)
  - Newspaper clipping, undated (Box 9, Folder (IV).94-100.5)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1771 October (Box 9, Folder (IV).101-105)
- Series XII. Prints and artwork
  This series documents du Simitière as both collector and artist. The material consists of collected drawings and sketches as well as du Simitière's own art work, and covers several broad topics. Included are alphabets of several languages, landscapes (largely West Indian), portraits, drawings of architecture and architectural elements, natural history sketches, and drafts of seals. The sketches and drawings are printed, pen and ink drawings, watercolors and pastels.
  This material is located within the Print Department at the Library Company of Philadelphia. The Print Department also houses cartoons, created by and collected by du Simitière, which are not catalogued in this finding aid.
  - [Liberty Pole, New York], 1770 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Chinese alphabet, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Irish alphabet, circa 1780-1781 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Arabic document (translation available), undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Vue d'optique of a horse and landscape, circa 1790 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified West Indian harbor (watercolor), circa 1758-1774 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Miniature stage design, undated (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - East front of Harvard Hall, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Plan of Harvard Hall, undated (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Various sketches and drawings, 1759-1783 (Box 11)
- Series XIII. Volume boards, undated (Box 10-11)
  The volume boards housed in this series are from disbound volumes housed elsewhere in the collection.
- Series XIV. Inventory of Du Simitière's American Museum, January 22, 1785 (Box 12)
  The inventory lists the contents of Du Simitière's American Museum, compiled after his death. The list includes books, works of art, as well as the contents of various cabinets of curiosity. 14 folio pages in manuscript, separated at most folds.
  *This item was added to the collection in 2017 and was not in the collection when first processed*
  - An Inventory and Appraisement of all the goods, chattels, & effects of Pierre Eugene Du Simitiere deceased, which have come to the posession of Matthew Clarkson and Ebenezer Hazard administrators of his estate., January 22, 1785 (Box 12, Folder 1)